这是二零一八年普通高等学校招生
全国统一考试英语科听力部分。
该部分分为第一、第二
两节。
注意。
回答听力部分时，请先将答案
标在试卷上。
听力部分结束前，你将有两分钟的时间
将你的答案转涂到答题卡上。
现在是听力试音时间。
We have different languages on different evenings.
Monday, Spanish, Tuesday, Italian, Wednesday, German, and Friday, French.
On Thursday, we usually have a meal in a restaurant for anyone who wants to come.
Well, that sounds great.
I really need to practice my French.
Okay. Well, if you can just give me your name and address, I'll send you the form
and some more information.
If you join now, you can have the first month free.
试音到此结束。
听力考试正式开始。
请看听力部分第一节。
第一节，听下面五段对话。
每段对话后有一个小题，
从题中。
中所给的
三个选项中，选出最佳选项。
听完每段对话后，你都有十秒钟的时间来回答
有关小题和阅读下一小题。
每段对话仅读一遍。
例如，现在你有五秒钟的时间
看试卷上的例题。
你将听到以下内容。
Excuse me, can you tell me how much the shirt is?
Yes, it's 9.15.
你将有五秒钟的时间，将正确答案
标在试卷上。
衬衫的价格为九磅十五便士。
所以你选择
项，并将其标在试卷上。
现在你有五秒钟的时间
James, you've been watching TV for the whole evening.
What's on? It's a science program on the origin of the universe.
I'll give a presentation on it in my class tomorrow.
Hello, do you have the best of Mozart?
Sorry, we've just sold out, but we can order one for you.
If you give us your number, we'll call you when the CD arrives.
We'd better be going now, or we'll be late for the train.
No rush, it's 8.30 now.
We still have two hours.
I am so tired of driving all those hours to work.
Yeah, I know what you mean.
I used to drive two hours to work each way, but now I live within walking distance
of my office.
I don't even need a bike.
Hi, Andy. I didn't see you in Professor Smith's class yesterday.
What happened? Well, I had a headache, so I called him and asked for sick leave.
The here. I'm thinking of going back to School?
第一节到此结束。
第二节。
听下面五段对话或独白。
每段对话或独白后有几个小题，
从题中所给的
三个选项中，选出。
最佳选项。
听每段对话或独白前，
你将有时间阅读各个小题，
每小题五秒钟。
听完后，各小题将给出。
五秒钟的作答时间。
每段对话或独白读两遍。
听下面一段对话，回答
第六和第七两个小题。
现在，你有十秒钟的时间
阅读这两个小题。
To study what?
Ecology. I'm interested in the relationship between humans and nature.
Cool. Is it what you studied years ago?
No, I majored in chemistry then.
The biggest mistake I made was leaving college in my last year and not completing my
education. So I'm thinking of going back to school.
School? To study what?
Ecology. I'm interested in the relationship between humans and nature.
Cool. Is it what you studied years ago?
No, I majored in chemistry then.
Listen Yes, of course.
听下面一段对话，回答
第八和第九两个小题。
现在。你有十秒钟的时间
阅读这两个小题。
The Grand Hotel opened in 1990, and it sits on the seaside along the South Coast
Highway. It is the most beautiful hotel here.
That sounds great.
And there are some restaurants outside, so at dinnertime, you'd have a lot of
choices. That's really nice.
I like to have some local foods while traveling.
What about the scenery around it?
The hotel has the best views of the Pacific Ocean.
Oh, I think I will love this hotel.
Good morning, madam.
I am your guide for this trip.
How lovely. Could you tell me about the hotel I'm going to stay at?
Yes, of course.
The Grand Hotel opened in 1990, and it sits on the seaside along the South Coast
Highway. It is the most beautiful hotel here.
That sounds great.
And there are some restaurants outside, so at dinnertime, you'd have a lot of
choices. That's really nice.
I like to have some local foods while traveling.
What about the scenery around it?
The hotel has the best views of the Pacific Ocean.
Oh, I think I will love this hotel.
听下面一段对话，回答
第十至第十二三个小题。
现在，你有十五秒钟的时间
阅读这三个小题。
Hi, Mike. Hi, Alice.
Nice to see you.
You don't often come here.
I usually have fast food delivered to my office.
Just came here for a change today.
The environment here is good, clean and relatively quiet.
Yeah, and I heard the food is tasty.
By the way, are you going to the concert tomorrow evening?
Yes, are you?
Yeah. Katherine was supposed to go with me, but she may have to work extra hours
tomorrow. Do you know anyone who might like to go?
No, but if you like, I can ask around.
Er, Joan might want to go.
Oh, yes. She's a great fan of classical music.
I'll give her a ring after lunch.
Hi, Mike. Hi, Alice.
Nice to see you.
You don't often come here.
I usually have fast food delivered to my office.
Just came here for a change today.
The environment here is good, clean and relatively quiet.
Yeah, and I heard the food is tasty.
By the way, are you going to the concert tomorrow evening?
Yes, are you?
Yeah. Katherine was supposed to go with me, but she may have to work extra hours
tomorrow. Do you know anyone who might like to go?
No, but if you like, I can ask around.
Er, Joan might want to go.
Oh, yes. She's a great fan of classical music.
I'll give her a ring after lunch.
听下面一段对话，回答
第。
十三至第十六四个小题。
现在你有二十秒钟的时间
阅读这四个小题。
Hi, I've only just arrived.
Oh, good. Now here are the keys.
Let's go in.
There are two apartments.
The one for rent is on the right.
Do come in.
Thank you. I like the carpet.
The color is nice, isn't it?
Yes, and this apartment is in good condition.
Here is your lounge.
Where would we eat?
There is this corner here, or you can use your kitchen.
Come and see.
The kitchen is quite small.
Yes, but it has everything.
Cooker, fridge, even a dishwasher.
And there are lots of cupboards.
Let me show you the bedrooms.
This is the smaller one.
It's a good size, though.
Now come into the other bedroom.
You can see the bathroom, too.
Yes, it is very nice, but I will have to ask my friend first, and we will come
together. I understand it is $800 a month.
Yes, but a few blocks downtown would be much more expensive.
Well, thank you.
I will be in touch.
Hi, I've only just arrived.
good. Now here are the keys.
Let's go in.
are two apartments.
The one for rent is on the right.
Do come in.
Thank you. I like the carpet.
The color is nice, isn't it?
Yes, and this apartment is in good condition.
Here is your lounge.
Where would we eat?
I don't know.
I I I don't don't don't don't Yes, it is very nice, but I will have to ask my friend
first, and we will come together.
I understand it is $800 a month.
Yes, but a few blocks downtown would be much more expensive.
Well, thank you.
I will be in touch.
know. don't know.
听下面一段独白，回答
第十七至第二十四个小题。
现在你有二十秒钟的时间
阅读这四个小题。
Thank you very much.
Thank you, Dr.
Johnson. Well, it is really great to be back at university again.
The thing that I wanted to tell you today is this.
is important. When I came to the U.S., I was only thinking about being a carpenter.
But I could not read the newspaper, and I could not understand the news on
television or movies or anything like this.
So I entered the City College to take English classes for foreign students.
I was very proud that I was going to a college, because no one in my family ever
went to any college or to any university.
You know, when you are 15 years old in my country, you finish school and then you
learn a trade, and that is exactly what I did.
When I was 15 years old, I learned how to be a carpenter.
A year later, I came to America.
Luckily, I met a very good teacher who encouraged me to take some math classes,
business classes, and history classes, and I became a full -time college student.
And today, when I look back, I am so happy because you never know where life will
take you. All of a sudden, I started making money because I was really good at math.
You know, how to work out everything with math is so important.
This is something that I learned when I started my own business, which is doing
really well. Thank you very much.
Thank you, Dr.
Johnson. Well, it is really great to be back at university again.
The thing that I wanted to tell you today is this.
is important. When I came to the U.S., I was only thinking about being a carpenter.
But I could not read the newspaper, and I could not understand the news on
television or movies or anything like this.
So I entered the City College to take English classes for foreign students.
I was very proud that I was going to a college, because no one in my family ever
went to any college or to any university.
You know, when you're 15 years old in my country, you finish school and then you
learn a trade, and that's exactly what I did.
When I was 15 years old, I learned how to be a carpenter.
A year later, I came to America.
Luckily, I met a very good teacher who encouraged me to take some math classes,
business classes, and history classes, and I became a full -time college student.
And today, when I look back, I'm so happy because you never know where life will
take you. All of a sudden, I started making money because I was really good at math.
You know, how to work out everything with math is so important.
This is something that I learned when I started my own business, which is doing
really well. The Thank you.
第二节到此结束。
现在，你有两分钟的时间将。从试卷上的答案
转涂到答题卡上。
Thank you. Thank you.
听力部分到此结束。